<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Tag: configuring | Francis's Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://jhjguxin.github.io/tags/configuring/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jhjguxin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-12T19:23:30+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://jhjguxin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Francis Jiang]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[864248765@qq.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Configuring Gedit for Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://jhjguxin.github.io/blog/2012/06/07/configuring-gedit-for-rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T10:34:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://jhjguxin.github.io/blog/2012/06/07/configuring-gedit-for-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Configuring Gedit for Rails</h2>

<p>I haven’t kept my feelings about IDEs hidden, I’m a big believer in using text editors instead.</p>

<p>I know, I should earn my chops and become a Vim guy, and some day I hope to sit down and make that conversion, but for now it’s all about Gedit for me. With a few plugins and a little TLC gedit can be a lighter version of the more powerful, more intensive ide.</p>

<p>The first thing we’re going to install gMate, an addon designed to make Gedit run like TextMate</p>

<blockquote>sudo add-apt-repository ppa:ubuntu-on-rails/ppa

sudo apt-get update</blockquote>


<blockquote>sudo apt-get install gedit-gmate</blockquote>


<p>Additionally we’re going to install the standard plugins package</p>

<blockquote>sudo apt-get install gedit-plugins</blockquote>


<p>Now lets fire up Gedit and turn on our preferences.</p>

<p>To get to our plugins go to Edit &gt; Preferences &gt; Plugins.</p>

<p>We’re going to enable the following options:</p>

<ul>
    <li>Snippets</li>
    <li>Code Comment</li>
    <li>Embedded Terminal</li>
    <li>Find in Files</li>
    <li>Rails Extract Partial</li>
    <li>Rails File Loader</li>
    <li>Session Saver (Optional)</li>
    <li>Smart Indent (Optional)</li>
    <li>Tab Switch (Optional)</li>
    <li>TextMate Style AutoCompletion</li>
</ul>


<p>This is going to enable a lot of different functionality, and while this is the setup I use, it may be more than you need.</p>

<p>Now if you’re in a ruby file and you type def, tabbing over will add the end and place you straight on the method name, control+tab will switch between documents, and syntax highlighting will work correctly in html.erb files.</p>

<p>Also, going to view &gt; bottom pane will display a terminal window that I find convenient for running irb.</p>

<p>While these instructions will enable a lot of different useful environments, and the target of this post was rails, I do have to sadly add that Google Go, which I cover quite often, does not, to my knowledge, have a plugin for Gedit currently.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
